Clint Andrew Hall

User Interface Engineer and Lead

CONTACT

resume@clintandrewhall.com https://www.clintandrewhall.com Kansas City, MO, US

PROFILES

GitHub: clintandrewhall LinkedIn: clintandrewhall Twitter: clintandrewhall Facebook: clint.hall

clintandrewhall Instagram:

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science, Rockhurst University

09/1997 - 08/2001

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I'm a Engineering Lead and User Interface Engineer. I work to make the web beautiful, both on its surface and beneath.

I'm a demonstrated expert in HTML, CSS and JavaScript, React/Flux/Relay, and more. I specialize in techniques promoting web agnostics, semantics, and accessibility. I'm comfortable with varying levels of skill in any web stack, having written and maintained code in JS, PHP, Java and Ruby-on-Rails. I currently prefer Node+React or React Native for most of my projects.

I'm a regular consumer and occasional contributor to open source projects and client APIs. If I have a suggestion for a website or application, I prefer to demonstrate the idea using an API rather than just describe it-- Code Wins Arguments.

I look for opportunities where I can make strong, direct and meaningful contributions to a team, to users and to the web. I'm comfortable functioning as both designer and engineer, advising on both the technical and aesthetic. I'm affable and good-natured, yet results-driven and competitive. I have extensive experience working remotely, particularly during my time at Facebook and Elastic.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Area Lead, Presentation Team - Kibana

October 2020 - Present Elastic

Most recently, the Kibana organization reorganized and created a new team: Presentation. This team is responsible for Canvas, Dashboard, and any other product considered a "presentation container". I've been named the Area Lead for this new team.

- kibana/51318: Coordinated completion of "Time to Visualize".
- kibana/88112: Plugin Services abstraction and shared component library. kibana/95435: "Labs" service for enabling experimental projects.

Area Lead, Canvas - Kibana

December 2018 — October 2020 Elastic

Soon after I began working at Elastic, I was named the new Area Lead for Canvas. I was responsible for overseeing and coordinating our technical efforts, representing the team across the org, and contributing significant enhancements.

This role was my first as an official Engineering Lead. During my tenure I coordinated projects for 1 major and 9 minor releases, including the General Availability (GA) release of Canvas from beta. I introduced a number of technologies and architecture

approaches that stabilized and enhanced the plugin, and oversaw migration of bespoke technology to the Kibana ecosystem, (e.g. expressions).

- kibana/31734: Significant React performance investigation.
- kibana/35087: Introduced Typescript.
- kibana/36252: Introduced internationalization architecture.
- kibana/38850: Introduced Storybook for rapid development and testing.
- kibana/46278: Built novel means of embedding Canvas Workpads.

Principal Software Engineer - Kibana

October 2018 - December 2018

Elastic

In October of 2018, I accepted a role with Elastic to work on Kibana, specifically a new, ground-breaking beta plugin called Canvas

User Interface Engineer

April 2015 — June 2018

Facebook NYC

When I first moved to the NYC Facebook office, I joined the Composer team for a "hack-a-quarter", converting the Composer to React, and then worked on the Share Dialog.

Eventually Events found themselves with a large number of React and Relay projects, so I rejoined my former team remotely. I built the new Events Dashboard and Permalink, and implemented many "under the hood" improvements.

- New Events Dashboard for desktop in Relay
- New Events Dashboard for the mobile site in XHP
- New Events Permalink for all web surfaces in XHP
- New React + Flux Composer, and the new Share Dialog using that component.
- New 'Minutiae' controls, the structured data (Photos, Activity, Tags) found in Composer.

User Interface Engineer

August 2013 — April 2015

Facebook Vancouver

In 2013 I joined the Vancouver office with an amazing cadre of engineers from all over the world. With a Canadian fiance, it made sense for me to bring Facebook experience (and culture) to a group of "n00bs".

While there, I worked on the Protect and Care team developing a new Messaging Inbox built in React. I also implemented the Open Graph Share dialog for FB Platform in XHP.

- New Help Center Inbox for desktop in React.
- New "How-to" panels for the Help Center
- New Platform Share Dialog for mobile and desktop in XHP.

User Interface Engineer

January 2012 — August 2013 Facebook HQ

I joined Facebook in 2012 as a User Interface Engineer (UIE) on the Mobile Core Web team. I then joined the Accessibility team to help make Facebook more useful to everyone on the web.

After several hackathons involving Events, I joined the team full time to rewrite the web experiences on both the mobile and main website.

Afterwards, I spent some time with the Platform team, reworking a number of different web flows, like OAuth, and embeddable components like Share, Hashtags and Topics.

- New OAuth flow dialogs for developers using Facebook.
- New Share, Hashtags and Topics plugins for developers.
- New mobile web experience for the Events Dashboard and Permalink.
- Improved the Accessibility of Facebook, including a new way to "see" photos.
- New core components for mobile web for product teams.

Web Evangelist

October 2009 — January 2012

Cerner Corporation

As Cerner's first Web Evangelist, I was responsible for advancing web best-practices to teams, both existing and emerging. I

basically served as ad-hoc advisor with respect to semantics, accessibility, web agnostics and the responsible use of CSS and JavaScript.

- New OpenID SDK for the iPhone.
- Redesigned a semantic search servive to use JSON-P
- "Proscenium", an experimental technique of compiling templates in JS libaries for isomorphic rendering.
- Spoke about Progressive Enhancement as a necessary philosophy.

Principal Architect

October 2010 — January 2012 Socially Adept Geek, LLC

In my spare time I operated a consultancy where I helped clients and friends with custom code, strategies and advice on their web projects.

I shuttered this consulting business as part of my agreement to work at Facebook.

Software Architect

January 2007 — October 2009 Cerner Corporation

For a several years I was a Software Architect for Healthe, enforcing cross-browser compatibility, semantic markup and accessibility, developing CSS layouts and advanced JavaScript controls, and conducting platform research. I would also prototype HTML code based on paper designs, allowing the team to communicate intent to clients, stakeholders, usability and engineers.

- Inculcated a comprehensive browser-agnostic web philosophy, massively improving accessibility, portability and performance.
- Invented the 'Web Bootstrapper', a patented technology that allowed semantic web pages to adapt to the heuristics of any device, dynamically.
- Consultant and mentor to teams and engineers on web technology and development.

Sr. Software Engineer

January 2005 — January 2007 Cerner Corporation

For several years I worked on the ePrescribing (eRx) and Community Health Record (CHR) solutions for treating Medicare populations in several states. I would interpret functional requirements into a coherent user interface and visual design.

- Proposed and built the "New Navigation" project, which was a radical redesign of the UI based on usability studies and feedback from sales.
- Novel architecture pattern discarding JSPs in favor of full modules of aggregate presentation components, adding entire
 workflows to any WAR using standard J2EE and Struts configurations.
- Mentored software engineers and other architects in semantic markup practices and prudent Javascript.

Application Developer

October 2003 — January 2005 Cerner Corporation

When I joined Cerner, I took on the role of Presentation Layer Developer for the "Web Experience" solution, specifically Order Management. I would design, document, and develop the UI for order placement, drug catalog browsing, and proactive interaction checking and alerting.

- Reusable, component-based rendering system which resulted in an 80% reduction in markup in JPSs, as well as sharing between solutions.
- Subject matter expert for most presentation layer technologies, and reviewed most of that code from my (and other) teams. I
 ended up teaching a few courses for new associates.

Application Developer II

June 2003 — October 2003 Sprint

I held a brief role at Sprint, transitioning from Accenture Outsourcing to Sprint PCS. I rolled on to the Architecture team, and was responsible for applying design patterns, creating interfaces to back-end applications, and overseeing code development across releases.

Outsourced Analyst

July 2001 — June 2003 Accenture

Employed as an Analyst in the Outsourcing organization for a number of client engagements.

- At a Wireless Telecom engagement, I wrote web-based Java interfaces for a customer care billing platform.
- At a Long Distance Telecom engagement, I was on-call and responsible for monitoring load balance and processing time on switches using SQL.
- At a Broadband Telecom engagement, I created test plans for development teams across the US and Canada.

Intern

January 1998 — January 2001 Symbol Technologies

I spent three summers writing complete web-based applications for quality control efforts.

SPFAKING

Redefining How We See Technology

October 2014

TEDx RenfrewCollingwood

I was invited to speak at TEDxRenfrewCollingwood about using metaphors to explain technology, to "bridge the gap" between what people believe software can do, and what it actually can do. I created an open-source website called metaphorical.ly where anyone could create a technology metaphor.

Web Presentation Layer Bootstrapping for Accessibility and Performance

April 2009

International Cross-Disciplinary Conference on Web Accessibility

I wrote a paper and delivered a talk about my findings using the Web Bootstrapper at Cerner in Madrid, Spain.

Bootstrapping Web Pages for Accessibility and Performance

April 2009

18th International World Wide Web Conference

I delivered a talk on the Web Bootstrapper I developed at Cerner at the WWW Conference in Madrid, Spain.

SP3D and the Lighthouse: Explorations in 3D Internet Learning

March 1999 SIGGRAPH

I was a speaker in the 'Playground' and 'Classroom' discussing the success of my 1997 and 1998 ThinkQuest websites, which used 3D graphics combined with Internet technology to teach difficult subjects to students of all ages.

WRITING

Web Presentation Layer Bootstrapping for Accessibility and Performance

April 2009

W4A

In this paper, I present a the Web Bootstrapper, a technique that allows a developer to write a single site while still providing multiple experiences, or "skins," without altering source or running costly client-side code. It is a process by which an accurate collection of only those static resources and metadata necessary for a unique experience be delivered passively, by the most performant means possible.

RECOGNITION

Irene Ryan Acting Scholarship

May 2001

KC/ACTF Region V Conference

Three-time nominee for excellence in Acting.

2nd Place - Arts and Literature

October 1997 ThinkQuest 1997

Created "Shakey's Place", a website about Shakespeare featuring a 3D Globe Theatre. Placed Second in Arts and Literature category totaling \$48,000 in scholarships. Team Leader, designed interface and 3D graphics, programmed Perl 5 scripts, designed HTML layout.